本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：天意    zlean    Silmar    soda    meredith
时间轴：Angelica     特效：Will
■
校对：ETSChina      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
-你好  又见面了  -你好
-Well, hello again.  - Hi!
希望我们没有太迟
I hope we're not too late.
不不不  时候刚好
No, no. Perfect timing.
斯坦  这是我丈夫沃尔特
Okay, Stan, this is my husband Walt.
你好  沃尔特  很高兴见到你
Hi. Good to meet you, Walt.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
-桑迪亚实验室的人是吧  -没错
- Sandia Laboratories, huh?  -Yeah.
我听说你们研发了不少好东西啊
I hear some pretty fascinating stuff goes on out there.
你知道的
Ah, well, you know--
最近在忙什么
Working on anything you can talk about?
我寻思着是不是某种大型空间激光器
I'm picturing giant space lasers.
我说的没错吧
Am I right?
说实话  我干的活你肯定觉得无聊
Honestly, what I do would bore you senseless.
大型空间激光器
Oh! But giant space lasers?
这个听上去挺棒的
Now, that sounds cool.
下次管理层开会  我会给他们提一提
I'll have to bring it up at our next staff meeting.
那我得要提成哦
Well, just remember I get a cut.
没问题  我们一言为定
All right, that's a deal.
就这儿了  亲爱的  怎么说
So this is it, honey. What do you say?
-你想参观一下吗  -当然
- Do you want to take a tour?  - Sure.
来吧
Okay.
这样吧  你们单独慢慢看
Look, how about I give y'all some privacy?
我去车里打几个电话
I'll go out to the car and make a few calls.
你们慢慢看  不着急
Take as much time as you need.
好的
All right. Good.
谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
人不错  不是急性子
He's actually a nice guy. He doesn't push.
对
Yeah.
你看到了  这里
So, as you can see, there's, uh...
这里挺通风
there's a kind of flow going on here.
-客厅也很棒  -不错
- It's a nice big living room.  - Yeah.
这是饭厅
And this is the dining area.
-饭厅是吧   -没错
- Ah, the dining area. Right.  - Yes.
还有
Oh, and, uh--
-游泳池  -游泳池不错
- It's got a pool.  - Oh, pool is nice.
后院有点小
Backyard could be a little bigger.
可以在这儿吃早餐
Um, and-- Oh, there's a breakfast bar
-感觉不错  -挺好
- kind of dealie here which is nice.  - Jesus.
你看  厨房也挺宽敞的
And, uh, I don't know, the kitchen's really spacious
电气用具也基本齐全
and, you know, got good appliances, and--
有几间卧室
How many bedrooms?
三间
Three.
给你说过了
Told you.
户型都不错
They're all pretty good size, and--
这是第一间
Oh, this is the first one here.
后面还有两间
And then there's two more at the back.
只有三间卧室吗
Only three bedrooms?
怎么说也得五间吧
I think we're gonna need at least five.
不觉得吗
Don't you think?
-五间  -是的
- Five?  - Yeah.
什么  我像这么能生的吗
What? Do I look like I'm about to drop a litter?
-不  不  -喂
- No, no, no, no, no, no.  - Dude.
不  我们最终会有三个孩子
No, we'll have three kids total, eventually.
但需要一间空房来当书房
But we'll need a spare room for a study
这样我就能在家工作  你也可以写作
so that I could work at home and you can write.
所以我觉得
Nah, I don't--
这儿小了点
I don't think this is gonna be enough.
好吧  那酒窖呢
Okay. Um, what about a wine cellar?
咱们肯定不能
I mean, we certainly cannot be expected
没有酒窖吧
to live without a wine cellar.
很好笑
Very funny.
我只是觉得咱们应该把眼光放高一点
I just think we need to set our sights high is all.
至少比这地方高
At least higher than here.
沃尔特  这是个很好的社区
Walt, this is a good neighborhood.
这里有所很棒的小学
It's got a good elementary
所以高中也应该不错
and supposedly a very good high school.
相信我
And believe me--
我都仔细比对过了
'cause I have definitely looked everywhere--
这儿价格真的不错
for our price range,
简直是物美价廉
this is as good as it gets.
价格再高点也不是问题
Well, then let's stretch our price range.
真的
Truly.
我的意思是  干嘛买个初级的房子
I mean, why buy a starter house
然后过个一两年又得搬家
when we'll have to move out in a year or two?
你赢彩票了吗
Did you win the lottery and not tell me?
我是认真的
I'm serious.
别这样  干嘛这么谨慎
Come on. Why be cautious?
人往高处走
We've got nowhere to go but up.
绝
命
毒
师
第三季
第十三集
喂
Yeah.
沃尔特  看见我们了吗
Walter, you see us?
看见了
Yeah, I see you.
我希望你能从车上下来
I'd like you to exit your vehicle
然后慢慢朝我们走过来
and start walking toward us.
然后呢
And then what?
然后我需要
I'm gonna need some...
保证
some kind of assurance.
我保证我能从这直接杀了你
I assure you I could kill you from way over here,
如果这能让你感觉好点的话
if it makes you feel any better.
沃尔特  你最近可没闲着
Walter, you've been busy.
把你的手
You want to put your arms out
抬起来
to the sides for me, if you would?
你知道我从周四开始就没睡觉
You know I haven't slept since Thursday?
我整晚都在外面给你擦屁股
I was out all night cleaning up after you.
我需要睡眠
I need my sleep.
你叫我别姑息折衷
You said no half measures.
没错
Yeah.
你要这么曲解  我也没办法
Funny how words can be so open to interpretation.
车修了吗
You get your car fixed?
还没
Not yet.
最好把车修好
You're gonna want to get your car fixed.
先把目前这档子事解决了再说吧
Let's see how this goes first.
情况恶化了吗
Has your condition worsened?
什么
Excuse me?
你的身体状况  恶化了吗
Your medical condition, has it grown worse?
据我所知  没有
Not that I know of, no.
-耳鸣吗  -不
- Is there a ringing in your ears?  - No.
是否看见亮光或是幻听
Are you seeing bright lights or hearing voices?
我很好  多谢关心
I'm quite well, thank you.
不  显然你不好
No. Clearly you are not.
有理智的人  可不会干出这样的事
No rational person would do as you have done.
解释一下吧
Explain yourself.
我的合伙人差点被人打死
My partner was about to get himself shot.
我不得不进行干涉
I intervened.
这种没用的瘾君子
Some worthless junkie--
你冒着把我们全暴露的危险  就为了他吗
For him you intervene and put us all at risk?
这种卑鄙小人
Some contemptible junkie
叫他和解  却连8个小时都管不住自己
who couldn't keep the peace for eight hours?
没错  他是管不住
That's right. He couldn't.
因为你的两个毒贩杀了个11岁的孩子
He was angry because those two dealers of yours
所以他很生气
had just murdered an 11-year-old boy.
我听说了
I heard about it.
他应该让我来处理
He should have let me take care of them.
也许吧
Maybe.
但也许他认为
Then again, maybe he thought
就是你下的命令
it was you who gave the order.
你在质问我
Are you asking me
是不是我下令杀那孩子的
if I ordered the murder of a child?
我永远不会那么问
I would never ask you that.
平克曼现在在哪里
Where is Pinkman now?
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
至少是千里之外了
A couple of time zones away, at least.
当然这只是我的猜测
Beyond that, I'd only be guessing.
因为他有够花一辈子的钱了
He has enough money to last forever.
他知道自己要亡命天涯
He knows he needs to keep moving.
你找不到他的
You'll never find him.
这倒不见得  沃尔特
I don't know, Walt.
你忘了我是干什么的吧
It's what I do, after all.
现在跟他没关系了
He's out of the picture.
我救了他的命  是我欠他的
I saved his life. I owed him that.
现在我跟他两清了
But now he and I are done,
不正合你意吗
which is exactly what you wanted, isn't it?
我一直认为你是个务实的人
You've always struck me as a very pragmatic man,
如果可以  我想和你谈谈选择的问题
so if I may, I would like to review options with you
你有两个选择
of which it seems to me you have two.
选择一
Option A--
此时此地  把我干掉
you kill me right here and now.
很明显这对你来说再容易不过了
Apparently, I have made that very easy for you.
你可以杀了我  没有目击者
You can kill me-- no witnesses--
再花上几个星期  几个月的时间
and then spend the next few weeks or months
追查杰西·平克曼的下落  把他也干掉
tracking down Jesse Pinkman, and you kill him too.
在我看来  这毫无意义
A pointless exercise, it seems to me.
不过这就是选择一
But that is Option A.
选择二呢
What is Option B?
我继续制毒
I continue cooking.
你我都把平克曼给忘了
You and I both forget about Pinkman.
就当什么都没发生过
We forget this ever happened.
就当是我们互惠而长远的合作中
We consider this a lone hiccup
的一次小插曲
in an otherwise long and fruitful business arrangement.
我比较倾向选择二
I prefer Option B.
你需要个新助手
You'd need a new assistant.
-我可以去找  -不
- I could get right on that.  - No.
这次我来选人
This time, I choose.
你的车
Your car.
去修一下
Get it fixed.
知道了
Yeah.
至于吗
Really?
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
谢谢
Thanks.
很高兴我能回来
It's good to be back.
那么  我们开始吧
Well, shall we?
当然  盖尔  开始吧
By all means, Gale, let's cook.
犀牛怎么样
What about that rhinoceros?
你觉得那适合当宠物吗
You think he'd make a good pet?
-不适合  - 不适合吗
- No.  - No?
你觉得当你叫它时
Don't you think if you called to him,
它会跑过来吃饭吗
he'd come running for his supper?
我打赌它会跑来
I'll bet he would. I bet he'd come running.
你好傻  爷爷
You're silly, Pop Pop.
确实有点
Well, a little.
但它可能会把东西都撞翻
But he'd probably knock everything over.
而且它还有个大鼻子
Plus, there's that big nose of his.
那不是鼻子  是角
That's not a nose. That's a horn.
是吗
Is that so?
它鼻子很小的
His real nose is little.
跟你在一起我能学到好多东西
I learn all kinds of things being with you.
好了  乖孙女  这些给你
Okay, June Bug, these are for you.
剩下的呢
What about the rest?
剩下的是我的
The rest are for me.
才不是呢
No, they're not.
你太老了  不适合玩气球
You're too old for balloons.
再老都不为过
Oh, you're never too old for balloons.
来抱抱  看到你妈妈了
Give me a hug. Oh, I see your mama.
快去吧
Don't keep her waiting.
再见  爷爷
Bye, Pop Pop.
再见  宝贝
Bye, baby.
我求求你  你不要杀我  你千万不要杀我
我不能死  我有三个小孩子
求求你  求求你  不要杀我
Please. Please, no.
我求你你不要杀我
周  你欠我个解释
Chow, do you have anything you want to tell me?
感谢上帝你来了
Thank God you're here.
他们囚禁我
They keep me prisoner.
他们囚禁你
They keep you prisoner.
我没为他们做任何事
I don't do nothing for them ever.
他们想逼我就范
They try and make me.
我拒绝了
I say no.
他们偷走了我的化学材料
They steal my chemicals.
我阻止不了
I can't stop them.
我只是个商人
I am businessman.
你是个商人
You're a businessman--
外面的那位女士
The lady out front--
女士  你还在那里吗
Hey, lady, are you still there?
问她还在不在
Ask her if she's still there.
潘  你还在吗
我当然还在  我还能去哪里啊
你们在干什么呀  我得赶回家了
我有小孩子要照顾  我老公一定急死了
你钱付不够  我前面死了个男人耶
她还在
She says yes.
她会开车吗
How's her driving?
开车  她开车开得好吗
Driving. Is she good behind the wheel?
很好  她开得很好
Good. She's good driver.
有驾照吗  可靠吗
Licensed? Dependable?
她有辆凯美瑞
She has a Camry.
很好
Good.
卡车明天一早就会到这儿
The trucks will be here first thing in the morning.
我强烈建议你
I strongly recommend
下次记得回我们电话
that you return our calls next time.
让她载你去医院吗
So have her drive you to the hospital.
鞋忘拿了
She's gonna need her shoe.
他们从哪截的货
Where did they cross?
好像是拉雷多
Laredo, looks like.
但他们没有派出最厉害的手下
They didn't exactly send their A players.
如你所言  只是帮派行为而已
But like you said, it's cartel, all right.
他们在找弱点下手
Probing for weakness.
貌似没成功
Well, they didn't find any.
有平克曼消息吗
What about Pinkman?
我正在调查
I'm making inquiries.
好了  第二步
Done. That's two?
关上吧
All right. Let's close it up.
拉下来
Bring it down.
准备
Ready?
很好  好了
Great. Okay.
搞定
We're good.
你可以摘掉面具了
You can take your mask off now.
那家伙不走吗
Does that guy ever leave?
不走
Nah.
什么时候开始的
When exactly did that start?
刚开始的
It's new.
我们...
We had a...
替代你的那位  出了点小插曲
We had a little drama with the person you replaced.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
不必  没事
No, it'll be fine.
会好起来的
Things will continue to smooth out,
一切都会好起来的
and, yeah, it'll be fine.
顺便问下  和我工作你有什么顾虑吗
By the way, if you're at all worried about working with me...
没  没有
No, I'm not.
因为不论上次我有什么缺点
Because whatever my shortcomings last time,
我希望从现在开始  一切都能完美
I intend for things to go perfectly from here on out.
所以  如果有什么...
So, if there is...
盖尔  你很棒
Gale, you're great.
真的
Seriously.
我只是...
I just...
所有事情  你怎样想
However you like things to be done
我们就怎样做
is exactly how we are gonna do them.
绝对的
Period.
从现在起
From here on out.
所以呢
So, uh...
请指导我吧
please teach me.
好
Okay.
盖尔  很高兴见到你
Gale. It's good to see you.
福林先生
Mr. Fring.
真是...
Wow. This is, uh...
我该事先打个电话的
I should have called first.
没有打扰到你吧
I'm not interrupting anything, am I?
没有  完全没有
No. No, not at all.
请进
Please come in.
要喝点什么  薄荷甜酒怎么样
Can I offer you something? Creme de Menthe?
不  不必  谢谢
Oh, no. No, thank you.
请恕我这般打扰
I'm sorry for the inconvenience.
一点也没打扰
Oh, no, no. It's no inconvenience.
我有事要和你商量
I need to talk to you about something...
一件很紧迫的事
something rather pressing.
我想知道  在必要的情况下
If push came to shove, I was wondering
你多久之后可以独立制毒
how soon you might be able to take over the lab yourself.
在助手的协助下
You and an assistant.
为什么
Why would...
为什么会有这种必要
Why would push come to shove?
沃尔特有没有跟你提起过
Has Walter ever talked to you
他是为何入这行的吗
about why he got into this particular line of work?
我猜我以为是  佣金丰厚的缘故
I guess I assumed it was because it pays so well.
这是自然  不过具体来说
Oh, it is, but specifically.
他有和你说过他的健康问题吗
Has he ever spoken to you about his health problems?
这不奇怪
Oh. I'm not surprised.
他不太喜欢和人交流
He's a very private person.
他有什么健康问题
What exactly are his health problems?
他患有癌症  时日无多
He's dying of cancer.
所以他才来干这个
It is why he does this,
为了养家糊口
to provide for his family,
他已经做到了
which he has accomplished.
他的家人以后将衣食无忧
They will never want for anything.
他保证了这一点
He's seen to that.
他还有多长时间
how long does he have?
这就是问题所在
That is very much the question.
他不愿意谈这件事
He does not want to talk about it,
每次我跟他提起...
and every time I bring it up with him...
我认为他还没完全接受这个事实
I don't know that he's fully accepted the reality of it.
不是我冷血
And not to sound cold-blooded,
我毕竟是个生意人
but I am running a business here.
不  我能理解
No, I... I understand.
我在这里...
I have...
投入了很多资金
a very large investment in this.
总开销非常大
There is so much overhead
我负担不起停工
that I can't afford to shut down,
哪怕一个星期也不行
not even for a week.
所以你能明白我的担忧
So you understand my concern
以及对不停工的迫切希望吧
and my desire for continuity?
明白  完全明白
I do, absolutely.
只要沃尔特愿意
Now, I intend to keep Walter on
我会留他一直工作
as long as he wants,
前提是他身体情况允许
assuming he's physically up to it.
但他既然不能或者不愿意
But as he cannot or will not
告诉我他还可以工作多久
tell me how long that might be,
我不得不为最坏的情况做好打算
I must prepare for the worst-case scenario.
最坏的情况
The worst-case scenario.
我想如果我们能...
I suppose if we had...
再在一起制几批货的话
at least a few more cooks together...
现在还没准备好吗
You don't think you're ready now?
他真的是...
Well, he is such a...
大师级的
a master.
总有我学不尽的知识
There's always more for me to learn.
可是我想如果我们能再...
But I'm thinking that if we had...
比如  一两批货
say, one or two more cooks?
一批
One more...
我想就可以了
I guess, would do it.
应该能行
I suppose.
我相信你  盖尔
I believe in you, Gale.
我知道一旦时机成熟
I know that when the time comes,
你一定会准备好的
you will be ready.
怎么了
What's up?
沃尔特
Walt?
那个...
Is there, um...
清理催化剂床有什么特殊诀窍吗
any particular trick to purging the catalyst bed?
没有  直接清理就是了
No, it's pretty straightforward.
到时候我会告诉你
I'll show you when we get there.
什么事
Yeah.
告诉他我在开会
Tell him I'm in conference.
你看不到我在开会吗
Can't you see I'm in conference?
我在找你的一名客户
I'm looking to find a client of yours.
希望你可以帮个忙  给我他的地址
I was hoping you could help me out with an address.
哪位客户
Which client?
杰西·平克曼
Jesse Pinkman.
电话簿上找找杰西·平克曼
Jesse Pinkman in the phone book Jesse Pinkman.
这个人怎么找呢
Hmm. How would one track him down?
我也想知道
I wonder.
你还没走
You're still here.
你给我仔细听好  索尔
I need your full attention, Saul.
我要杰西·平克曼当前的行踪
Jesse Pinkman current whereabouts.
你赶紧告诉我  就可以继续享受你这个
The sooner you tell me, the sooner you can get back
天知道是什么的鬼东西
to whatever the hell this is exactly.
你当我是高年级纠察员吗  "当前的行踪"
What am I, eight-grade hall monitor? "Current whereabouts."
迈克  我实话跟你说
Let me tell you something, Mike...
你老实躺着
You are good right there.
我也找个舒服地方坐
Now, let's both get comfortable.
我说我要找平克曼
Now, when I say I'm looking for Pinkman,
你我都心知肚明  对吧
we both know why, don't we?
你给我装糊涂
And you pretending otherwise
只会浪费我的时间
only wastes my time
只会惹恼我
and serves to annoy me.
迈克
Mike, uh,
律师这行有它的规矩
there are rules to this lawyer thing.
是吗
Is that right?
是
Yeah.
律师-当事人保密特权  这很重要
Attorney-client privilege. That's a big one.
我也同样在为你保密
And that's something I provide for you.
所以如果我出卖平克曼
So if I give up Pinkman, well,
你就得问了
then you're gonna be asking
索尔这么轻易出卖他们
"Old Saul gives 'em up pretty easy.
怎能保证他不出卖我呢
What's to keep him from giving me up?"
看吧  这样哪还有信任
You see? So then where's the trust?
我可以把你活埋到沙漠里  你信吗
I trust the hole in the desert I'd leave you in.
也对
Yeah, it's an argument.
所以...
So...
别逼我把你打成瘸子
don't make me beat you till your legs don't work.
告诉我哪里能找到他
Now tell me where to find him.
识时务者为俊杰
You know it's the right thing.
我不能说  迈克
I can't tell you, Mike.
好吗
All right, I--
听我说  我要是告诉你了
Look, if I was to tell you,
我就...我良心过不去
I just-- I couldn't live with myself.
对不起
I'm sorry.
但是万一我把地址
But who's to say I didn't write
写在日程表上
the address down in my day planner?
或是草稿纸上
Or on a scratch piece of paper somewhere?
出于职业需要  我记下了地点
Who's to say I didn't write down a location
但结果不小心被人看见了
strictly for my own professional use?
请别碰我桌上任何东西
Do not touch anything on my desk.
我要出去一下  给我自己泡杯雀巢咖啡
I'm gonna leave the room, make myself a Nescafe.
我这是在罩着你
I'm just looking out for you, that's all.
就像是母鸡护小鸡
Like a mother hen.
相信我
Believe me,
洗钱已不是过去那回事了
money laundering ain't what it used to be.
真怀念八十年代
God, do I miss the '80s.
你这是白费功夫
Wasting your time.
我要买洗车场  说完了
I'm buying the car wash. End of story.
看一眼这地方  你就会喜欢上的
Well, one look at this place, you're gonna fall in love, so--
怎样  我说的没错吧
Huh? Was I right?
打着灯笼也找不到
Where else are you gonna find
这种只收现金  而且还这么好玩的地方
a cash-only business that's this much fun?
除非是那种[挂按摩院招牌的]妓院
Unless we're talking massage parlors,
不过我没找到
and I don't see it.
进来瞧瞧
Shall we?
你玩过激光枪战游戏吗
You ever actually play laser tag?
是个不错的有氧运动  而且还能朝小孩子开枪
It's good cardio. Plus you get to shoot at kids.
那边过去有碰碰车
You got your bumper cars over there down that way.
游乐场在这里
Got your arcade right here.
最新潮的电子游戏全有
All the latest video games.
小吃吧在那边儿
Snack bar is over there.
可以卖啤酒给家长
Nothing stopping you from selling beer to the parents.
是笔全新的收入
That's a whole new revenue stream.
行了行了
All right, enough.
我们安全了
We're good.
我的老天爷
Holy Christ.
安全了
We're good?
你觉得这种情况叫安全吗
This constitutes good where you're from?
我的车被人窃听
My car is bugged.
我只是说有可能被窃听
I said maybe-- maybe--
还被人跟踪
I'm being followed.
你他妈这次让我淌的是什么浑水
What the hell have you gotten me into?
我自己的私人侦探
My very own P.I.
跑来威胁  要打断我的腿
is threatening to break my legs.
就好像玛格侬威胁
That's like Thomas Magnum threatening
那个神经兮兮的小胡子[美剧私家侦探玛格侬]
that little prissy guy with the mustache.
太过分了
Over and above.
这早超过了我能给你提供的服务范围
Service-wise, is is over and above.
要是你我能躲过这一劫
You and I survive this,
我真要重新考虑加钱了
oh, I'm seriously rethinking my pricing.
没错  还有你
Yeah. And that goes
你要双倍  嬉皮小子
double for you, Hip-Hop.
那家伙不是傻子
My guy's no dummy. Right?
我们只有24小时
So I give us maybe 24 hours
赶在他发现地址是假的之前
before he figures out that address goes nowhere.
你们做好你们的事  赶紧的
You guys do your thing. Make it snappy.
我去看看有没有俄罗斯方块可以玩
I'll go see if they have Tetris or something.
你怎么样
How are you holding up?
你呢
You?
我干回我的老本行了
I got my old job back.
至少在盖尔接手之前  他们不会杀我
At least until they kill me and Gale takes over.
盖尔是他们的人  对吧
He's their boy, huh?
没错
He's their boy.
你觉得你还剩多少时间
How long you think you've got?
他问了我很多问题
Well, he asks a lot of questions
关于制毒过程的
about the cooking process.
我尽量含糊其辞
I try to be as vague as possible,
但那个维克多一直在监视着我
but I got that guy Victor watching me,
我说的每句话他都听着
listening to every word I say.
也许我还活着的唯一原因
Maybe the only thing that's saving me
是盖尔的过度严谨
is Gale's fastidiousness.
一旦他有把握了
Once he feels confident
掌握了我全部方法
that he knows my entire method...
那我们怎么办
So what do we do?
你知道该怎么办
You know what we do.
一定还有别的路子
There's got to be some other way.
也许直接自首对你比较好
Maybe it's better for you to just go to the cops.
对吧
All right?
我也不敢相信自己嘴里说出这话
I mean, I can't believe I'm saying that at all,
但是为了你家人着想
but for your family?
缉毒局肯定巴不得抓到你这样的人
The DEA would love you.
还有你可以透露给他们多少黑幕
All the shit you could tell them?
联邦证人保护  是很好的选择
Federal Witness Protection, that's a good deal.
至于我  我会自己跑路
As for me, I'll hit the road, yo.
我能逃得掉
I mean-- I'll make it.
我们的确风光过
We had a-- We had a good run.
但已经结束了
But it's over.
绝不找缉毒局
Never the DEA.
制毒不能停止
The cook can't stop.
这一点我确定无疑
That's the one thing I'm certain of.
货不能断
Production cannot stop.
古斯可担不起断货
Gus can't afford to.
所以假如我是他唯一的制毒师
So if I'm the only chemist that he's got,
那我就有了筹码
then I've got leverage.
能让我活命
And leverage keeps me alive.
也能让你活命  这点还是能保证的
It keeps you alive, too. I think I can see to that.
如果我是他唯一的制毒师
If I'm the only chemist that he's got.
我下不了手  怀特老师
I-- I can't do it, Mr. White.
就像你说的  我...
Like you said, I'm--
我不是个...
I'm not a...
我下不了手
I can't do it.
那我来
I'll do it.
我需要
I'm gonna--
我需要你的帮助
I'm gonna need your help.
他们日日夜夜都
I mean, they're watching me
在监视我
day and night.
我根本没机会和盖尔独处
They never leave me alone with Gale, not for a moment.
而且  我甚至都不知道他住哪儿
Hell, I don't even know where the man lives.
黄页上找不到他
He's not in the phone book.
在网上也查不着
I can't find him on the Internet.
我不能在实验室动手
I can't do it in the lab.
维克多一直在那儿
Victor's always there.
但如果能够给我哪怕一个小时
But if I could just...
摆脱掉维克多
shake Victor for even an hour one night,
我想那么
I think then that...
也许我就能
I may be able to...
把这件事弄成一场意外
make it look like an accident.
一定还有别的办法的
There's got to be some other way.
我洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
但事情到了你我与他  只能存活一方的境地
But when it comes down to you and me versus him--
我只能说抱歉了
I'm sorry,
真的很抱歉
I'm truly sorry--
死的必须是他
but it's gonna be him.
你是我唯一的优势
You are the only edge that I've got,
他们还不知道你在城里
as long as they don't know that you're in town.
我需要你跟踪他
But I need you to track him.
给我他的地址
Get me his address,
其他的我来做
and I'll do the rest.
听着  杰西  我救过你的命
Look, I saved your life, Jesse.
你这次能救我吗
Are you gonna save mine?
告诉我  你找到他了
Please tell me you found him.
胡安塔波林荫大道  6353号  6号公寓
6353 Juan Tabo Boulevard, Apartment 6.
还在听吗
You there?
恩  是的
Uh, yeah.
胡安塔波林荫大道  6353号  6号公寓  知道了
6353 Juan Tabo, Number 6. Got it.
他在家吗
He's home?
在
Yep.
那地方有人监视吗
Anyone watching the place?
貌似没人监视
No. Looks pretty much wide open.
你打算什么时候行动
When are you gonna do it?
今晚
Tonight.
等天黑
Once it gets dark.
怀特老师  别这么做
Don't do this, Mr. White.
求你了
Please.
去自首吧
Go to the cops.
出事了
We got a problem.
实验室里有些化学物品泄漏了
Some kind of chemical leaking in your lab.
你得跟我走一趟
You gotta come with me.
我  我开车跟着你
I'll, uh-- I'll follow you.
他们让我带你去  我就得带你去
They tell me to bring you, I bring you.
来吧  上车吧
Come on, get in the car.
我不太懂  也许是某个桶漏了
I don't know if it's a barrel leak or what,
但下面真的很臭
but you got something mighty stinky down there.
你先请
After you.
沃尔特  你越快找出原因
Walter, the sooner you figure out what this is,
我们就都能早点回家
the sooner we all go home.
求你别这样
Please don't do this.
迈克
Mike...
你不必这样做的
you don't have to do this.
不幸的是  我必须得这么做  沃尔特
Yeah. Unfortunately, I do, Walter.
请下楼
Downstairs.
我会免费制毒
I'll cook-- I'll cook for free.
不会再有任何麻烦了
And there won't be any more trouble.
-我向你保证  -不行
- I promise you. - No.
-好吗  让我和古斯谈谈  -不行
- Okay, if I could just talk to Gus, - No.
-我相信他会明白的  -不行
- I know I can make him understand. - No.
-如果我能和古斯谈谈  -不行沃尔特
-If I can talk to Gus-- No. Walter?
我能说服他的
...I can convince him, okay?
求你了  求你让我
Just let me, please-- Please.
-求求你让我和他谈谈  -闭嘴
- Please let me talk to him! - Shut up!
闭嘴
Shut up.
我不能这么做
I can't do it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我可以告诉你杰西·平克曼在哪
I'll give you Jesse Pinkman.
好吗  像你说的  他才是问题
Okay? Like you said, he's the problem.
他一直都是个麻烦  如果没有他
He's always been the problem. Without him, we would--
他  他就在城里
And he's-- he's in town, all right?
你找错了地方  他不在弗吉尼亚州
He's not in Virginia or wherever the hell you're looking for him.
他就在这儿阿尔布开克
He's right here in Albuquerque,
我可以带你去找他
and I can take you to him.
我能带你直接找到他
I'll take you right to him.
-怎么说  -他在哪儿
- What do you say?  - Where is he?
现在  你给我地址
Right now. You give me an address.
我  我不知道
I-- I don't-- He moves.
他没固定的位置  但如果能让我打电话
He moves around, but if you let me call him--
别  求你了
No, no, please.
不  只是电话
No, I just-- My phone.
只是  只是我的电话
I'll just-- It's just my phone.
我打给他  约他见面
I'll call him, and I'll have him meet me.
好吗  可以吗
All right? Okay?
可以吗
Okay?
你动手了吗
Did you do it?
怀特老师
Mr. White?
你动手了吗
Did you do it?
不  我没动手
No, I didn't do it.
我现在不能动手
I can't now.
必须由你来动手了
It's gonna have to be you.
什么  不行  老兄
What? No way, man.
听我说  你比我们离他近
Listen to me. You're closer than we are.
比我们快20分钟
You'll have about a 20-minute lead.
他们把我带到洗衣房  要杀了我
They've got me at the laundry, and they're going to kill me.
杰西  马上动手  快去
Jesse, do it now! Do it-- Do it fast!
马上就动手  杰西
Do it now! Jesse!
我的天
Oh, my God.
告诉我这到底是怎么回事
Just what the hell was that exactly?
你可能得缓一缓再杀我了
You might want to hold off.
是吗  为什么
Yeah? Why?
因为你的老板会需要我
Because your boss is gonna need me.
胡安塔波林荫大道  6353号  6号公寓
6353 Juan Tabo, Apartment 6.
没错
Yeah.
你好
Hi.
有什么事吗
How can I help you?
想要什么  尽管拿走
Take whatever you want.
我有钱  我有
I have money. I have--
我有很多钱
I got a lot of money.
我有
I have--
求求你别这么做
Please don't do this.
求求你别
You don't-- You--
求你
You--
你大可不必这样
You don't have to do this.